Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Writings and Speeches, 1912-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Open Files, 1912-1993 and undated
  - Yuspeh, Sonia, (8 folders)
    - 1983. Article. Pitfalls in the Product Life Cycle. J. Walter Thompson News, May (Box 53)
    - 1983. Article. Radical Potential of Cable Advertising (with Garth Hallberg). Journal of Advertising Research, Aug./Sept. (Box 53)
  - Multiple Authors, (4 folders)
    - 1978. Speech. JWT Ltd. Media Group presentation to the television industry (Box 53)
    - 1983-1991. Other writing. Various writings on advertising research (Box 53)
    - 1993. Speech. Are Canada's English Consumers Different Enough to Warrant Distinct Advertising? (Jack Cronin, Graham Peters, Angus Reid) (Box 53)
    - 1993. Article. Convergent Findings from ARS and BehaviorScan: Empirical Foundation for Improving Advertising's Track Record (Box 53)
  - Unattributed Authors, (11 folders) (Box 54)
    - 1982. Other writing. Presentation: Advertising in Japan (JWT Tokyo) (Box 54)
    - 1983. Other writing. Presentation: JWT (Box 54)
    - Circa 1985. Other writing. Presentation: The Egg and I (Box 54)
    - 1985. Other writing. Report: Focus Group Interview: Benefits and Limitations (Box 54)
    - 1988. Other writing. Presentation: If It's Old Hat, It Isn't News (Box 54)
    - 1989. Other writing. Presentation: Food Market in Canada (Box 54)
    - 1990. Other writing. Presentation: Lifestages (Box 54)
    - 1992. Other writing. Presentation: Marketing and Advertising in the Global Village (Box 54)
    - Undated. Other writing. Report: The Issue of One or More than One Agency (Box 54)
    - Undated. Other writing. Presentation: Lifestages (Box 54)
    - Undated. Speech. Speech from Frankfurt Office (Box 54)
- Restricted Files
  [Materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for 15 years from the date of creation]
  - Ashley, Susan R. (Box 55)
    - 1994. Speech. How to Effectively Compete Against Private-Label Brands (Box 55)
  - Burns, Ron
    - 1994. Speech. Given to JWT Toronto (Box 55)
  - Clements, George, (4 folders)
    - 1994. Speech. Advertising: Art or Science (Box 55)
    - 1994. Speech. Changing Nature of Retail Marketing (Box 55)
    - 1994-1996. Other writing. Understanding Quebec (report) (Box 55)
  - Furr, John
    - 1994. Speech. Who is J. Walter Thompson? (Box 55)
  - Hall, Chris
    - 1997. Other writing. Promise and Power of Confidence (open letter to World Partners Council) (Box 55)
  - Jeffrey, Bob, (2 folders)
    - 2000. Other writing. Presentation to North American Managers' Meeting (Box 55)
  - Jones, Chris
    - 1995. Speech. Given in Rome (Box 55)
  - Madsen, Hunter
    - 1994. Other writing. Advertising, 2000 AD (report) (Box 55)
  - Manning, Burton, (2 folders)
    - 1994. Speech. Quality and Cost in Advertising (Box 55)
    - 1995. Other writing. Tokyo staff briefing (Box 55)
  - Marans, David
    - 1995. Speech. Look at Cable TV (Box 55)
  - Unattributed Authors
    - 1994. Other writing. Presentation: Coffee (Box 55)
- JWT Creative Forum
  In mid-1966, the Television, Copy, and Art Departments were integrated into the Creative Department, headed by Walter F. (Chip) Meads as Management Supervisor. In the New York Office, seven operating units were established, each run by a Creative Supervisor, and each having its own writers, art directors, television producers, and traffic persons. A Special Supplement to the 1966 July 29 issue of the J. Walter Thompson Company News (housed in the J. Walter Thompson Company. Newsletter Collection) contains additional information about the Creative Department and its staff. The Creative Forum Papers, dating from 1966 to 1968, consisted of copies of 23 speeches and articles produced by JWT staff and distributed to members of the newly organized Creative Department.
  - Title List:
    - 1966. 1. Creative Vitality, Life Blood of Our Business, Dan Seymour (Box 55)
    - 1966. 2. Ads Are Like People, Chip Meads (Box 55)
    - 1966. 3. Mechanism of Hope to All Would-Be Fellinis, Fred Kittel (Box 55)
    - 1966. 4. Humor in Advertising--When Does It Pay? Barney Daniels (Box 55)
    - 1966. 5. Five Basic Human Needs, James Webb Young (Box 55)
    - 1966. 6. Dramaturgy for Minute Movies, Matthew Harlib (Box 55)
    - 1966. 7. Short Journey from NY to Princeton, or Advertising Without Tears, Gene Hill (Box 55)
    - 1966. 8. Relationship Between Researchers and Creative People, Stephen King (Box 55)
    - 1966. 9. Conform with the Non-Conformists, Bev Corbin (Box 55)
    - 1966. 10. Thompson T-Square (Box 55)
    - 1966. 11. Style in Advertising, Robert Westerfield (Box 55)
    - 1967. 12. Copywriters Thoughts on Copywriting, Harriet Rex (Box 55)
    - 1967. 13. On Making Lasting Memories, Dennis Schmidt (Box 55)
    - 1967. 14. Memorandum to Henry Schachte, James F. Barnum, MD (Box 55)
    - 1967. 15. What the Creative Person Should Expect from the Account Man--And Vice Versa, Jack Bernhardt (Box 55)
    - 1967. 16. TV and the Billion Dollar Lesson, William Tyler (Box 55)
    - 1967. 17. Advertising and the Principles of War, James Webb Young and RTC (Box 55)
    - 1967. 18. Funny Thing Happened on Our Way to the Answer Print, Granger Tripp (Box 55)
    - 1967. 19. Advice to a Young Man Who Wants to Succeed, Don Fitzsimmons (Box 55)
    - 1967. 20. Only Way to Nirvana, Jane Field (Box 55)
    - 1967. 21. What Price TV Commercials, Sel Shillinglaw (Box 55)
    - 1968. 22. New Creativity (Box 55)
    - 1968. 23. Crux of Creativity, Lawrence T. D'Aloise (Box 55)